Guide to the Jackie Boschok Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Jackie Boschok papers
1979-2013
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5688
Boschok, Jackie,$d1952-
17.85 cubic feet 27 boxes
2 oversize folders
Papers of a union representative and activist, and advocate for women in unions
Jackie Boschok (b. April 24, 1952) was a 30-year member, employee, and officer of the International Association of Machinists (IAM) 751. Boschok was also an officer in the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Puget Sound chapter as well as a member of the organization's national board. Boschok first became active in the union as soon as she started working at Boeing in 1980, working in a variety of positions and holding a variety of offices including steward and local lodge offices including recording secretary; treasurer; and auditor. Boschok served for seven years on the IAM District Council and worked as a Business Representative beginning in 2001, Union Organizer, and Health and Benefits Representative beginning in 2009. Boschok also served on the Snohomish County Labor Council from 1993-2010, serving on their Executive Board for 10 years and serving on its Community Services Committee. Boschock was a member and leader of the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) beginning in 1979 and in 1991 became a member of the national Executive Board. Boschok also served on the Washington State Labor Council's Women's Committee from 1994 to 2008, chaired the District 751 Women's Committee beginning in 2006, and served on the United Way of Snohomish County Board of Directors for six years.
Arranged into 2 accessions:
Accession no. 5688-001, Jackie Boschok papers, 1979-2010
Accession no. 5688-002, Jackie Boschok papers, 1980-2013
Personal papers documenting Boschok's career with the International Association of Machinists (IAM) 751 and an officer in the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Puget Sound chapter as well as the organization's national board. The collection includes publications, ephemera, correspondence, class materials, stickers, and artifacts, including t-shirts from various local and national labor organizations and campaigns.
Open to all users.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Boschok, Jackie,$d1952-$vArchives; Labor$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Labor union members$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Goodwill Games; Minutes (Records); Records (Documents); Business correspondence; Periodicals; Newsletters; Newspapers; Instructional and educational works; Ephemera; Mugs (Cups); T-shirts; International Association of Machinists; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.).$bPuget Sound Chapter; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Women; Washington (State); Seattle
- Jackie Boschok papers, 1979-2010; 5688-001; 16.32 cubic feet 22 boxes; 2 oversize folders
  The collection is arranged into five series:
  Series I: Jackie Boschok Professional Records
  Series II: Jackie Boschok Personal Records
  Series III: Publications
  Series IV: Educational/Training Materials
  Series V: Artifacts
  Series I is divided into subseries by creator type, and further divided into subseries by the creating body. Series III is divided into subseries based on their creator. Series II and IV are divided into subseries based on their subject matter. Series V is divided into subseries based on material type. Files within each subseries are arranged chronologically.
  This collection of records, publications and artifacts documents the various union activities of Jackie Boschok. While most of Jackie’s personal records are from the 1980s, the bulk of professional records and publications are from the 1990s-2000s. The records show the widespread involvement Jackie Boschok had across numerous unions and community groups, including her particular emphasis on the progression of women’s rights within both the workplace and the union. The largest part of the collections is Series I: Jackie Boschok Professional Records, which details the day-to-day activities, as well as special events, for unions and other labor coalitions of which Jackie Boschok served as a member and/or officer. At the end of Series I is Subseries B: Boeing Company Records, which highlights the relationship of Boeing and its employees, as well as detailing the Employee Community Fund, which consists of voluntary employee paycheck deductions donated to non-profits in the local community. Series II: Jackie Boschok Personal Records highlight Jackie’s personal employment, education, politics and union involvement. Of particular note is Subseries C: Jackie Boschok’s Political Involvement, which show her support for women’s rights, including the Equal Rights Amendment and a women’s right to choose. Also of interest is Subseries D: Seattle Goodwill Games/Rotary District 503 Goodwill Exchange gives a glimpse into the experience of housing Russian house guests during the Seattle Goodwill Games of 1990. Series III: Publications consists of journals, newspapers and newsletters published by the International Association of Machninists (IAM), the Coalition of Local Union Women (CLUW) and Boeing. These publications give insight into the pertinent issues concerning women in unions as well as unions at large at both local and national issues. Series IV: Educational Materials makes up a large part of the collection, with materials relating to various types of education pertinent to a union members: union (negotiating/collective bargaining), legal, workplace, technology and sexual harassment/domestic violence/workplace violence. Series V: Artifacts consists of five full boxes of artifacts, the bulk of which are related to the International Association of Machinists (IAM), but the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), United Way and Boeing are also represented. Of particular note is Subseries H: Strike Artifacts, which includes official IAM press scrapbooks and picket signs relating to strikes that occurred between 1989 and 2003. Also worth noting are the hundreds of pro-union and women’s rights buttons/pins and stickers in Subseries D and E, which were collected by Jackie between 1980 and 2010.
  Open to all users.
  Donor: Jacelyn "Jackie" M. Boschok, March 7, 2012
  - JACKIE BOSCHOK PROFESSIONAL RECORDS, SERIES I
    Series I is divided by creator type: Subseries A: Union Records and Subseries B: United Way of Snohomish County (UWSC) and Subseries C: Boeing Company Records. Subseries I: Union Records is further divided by the official creating body: Part 1: IAM 751, Part 2: Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), Part 3: AFL-CIO, Part 4: Washington State Labor Council (WSLC) and Part 5: Snohomish County Labor Council (SCLC). Within each subseries, files are arranged chronologically.
    The series consists of meeting minutes, agendas, reports, memoranda and correspondence that give insight into the day-to-day workings of local union and labor coalitions, as well as the relationship between local unions and their national-level counterparts. Additionally, this series includes the brochures, handouts, reports, agendas and meeting minutes relating to special union events, such as conventions, summits, strikes, banquets and fundraisers.
    - Union Records, Subseries A
      - Part 1: International Association of Machinists (IAM)
        - IAM International
          - IAM Human Rights & Women's Department Materials, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 5/16)
          - IAM International Materials, 1988-2010 (Box-folder 5/13-15)
          - IAM Grand Lodge Convention, 1992 (Box-folder 5/17-18)
          - IAM Collective Bargaining Agreement, 2008 (Box-folder 9/22)
          - IAM Constitution, 2009 (Box-folder 9/24)
        - IAM 751
          - IAM District Lodge 751 Machinists Non-Partisan League (MNPL) cookbook, circa 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 9/23)
          - IAM 751 Union Business Representatives Sheets, circa 1980-2010 (Box-folder 5/3)
          - IAM 751 Materials, 1988-2007 (Box-folder 5/1-2)
          - IAM Union Elections, 1992-2004 (Box-folder 12/6)
          - IAM 751 1995 Strike and Rally, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 11/4)
          - IAM National Community Services Documents, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 14/1)
          - IAM 751 Materials, 2003 (Box-folder 5/4)
          - Proceedings: IAM 36th Grand Lodge Quadrennial Convention, 2004 (Box-folder 5/7)
          - IAM District 751 Worker's Rights Conference, 2004 (Box-folder 9/12)
          - Aerospace Industry Summit, 2007 (Box-folder 5/5)
          - Governor's First Aerospace Summit, 2007 (Box-folder 5/6)
          - IAM 751 Women's Committee
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 9/19)
            - IAM District 751 Hear Us Roar Women's Conference, 2000 (Box-folder 9/18)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2001 (Box-folder 9/17)
            - IAM District 751 What Women Want Conference, 2001 (Box-folder 9/16)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2002 (Box-folder 9/15)
            - IAM 751 Women's Committee Sponsored Flight for Sight Fun Run to Beneft Guide Dogs of America (GDA)
              - IAM 751 Women's Committee Sponsored Flight for Sight Fun Run to Beneft Guide Dogs of America (GDA) fliers, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 15/1)
              - First Annual Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2002 (Box-folder 15/11)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2003 (Box-folder 15/10)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2004 (Box-folder 15/9)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2005 (Box-folder 15/8)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2006 (Box-folder 15/7)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2007 (Box-folder 15/6)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2008 (Box-folder 15/4-5)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2009 (Box-folder 15/3)
              - Flight for Sight Fun Records, 2010 (Box-folder 15/2)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2003 (Box-folder 9/13-14)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2004 (Box-folder 9/11)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2005 (Box-folder 9/10)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2006 (Box-folder 9/8-9)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2007 (Box-folder 9/5-7)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2008 (Box-folder 9/4)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2009 (Box-folder 9/2-3)
            - IAM District 751 Women's Committee Records and Documents, 2010-2011 (Box-folder 9/1)
        - IAM/Boeing Joint Programs, 1990-2010 (Box-folder 2/4-6)
      - Part 2: Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW)
        - National CLUW
          - National CLUW Documents, circa 1980s-2000s (Box-folder 10/3)
          - CLUW Convention Coverage, 1984-2007 (Box-folder 10/2)
          - National CLUW Documents, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 10/17)
          - National CLUW Documents, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 10/16)
          - National CLUW Documents, 1994 (Box-folder 10/14-15)
          - National Health Care Reform, 1994 (Box-folder 10/18-19)
          - National CLUW Documents, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 10/12-13)
          - National CLUW Documents, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 10/9)
          - National CLUW Documents, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 10/8)
          - CLUW National Executive Board Meeting, Washington, D.C., 2005 (Box-folder 10/6)
          - CLUW 13th Biennial Convention, Detroit, Michigan, 2005 (Box-folder 10/7)
          - National CLUW Documents, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 10/5)
          - National CLUW Documents, 2009-2011 (Box-folder 10/4)
        - Puget Sound CLUW
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Documents, 1974-1993 (Box-folder 6/1)
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Documents, 1994 (Box-folder 6/2)
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Documents, 1995 (Box-folder 6/3)
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Documents, 1996-2010 (Box-folder 6/7)
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Records Maintained by Recording Secretary Jackie Boschok, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 6/4-5)
        - CLUW New Technology Committee
          - Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - New Technology Committee Records by Recording Secretary Jackie Boschok, 1995-2005 (Box-folder 6/8)
          - CLUW New Technology Committee Resources, Part 1/2, 1995-2005 (Box-folder 6/9-10)
      - Part 3: AFL-CIO
        - Union Plus/Union Privilege Publications, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 13/1)
        - AFL-CIO National Community Services Documents, 1985; circa 1980s; 2001-2002 (Box-folder 13/2)
        - AFL-CIO Resources, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 6/12-14)
        - AFL-CIO Working Women Working Together Conference Records, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 9/20-21)
      - Part 4: Washington State Labor Council (WSLC)
        - WSLC (WA State Labor Council) Women's Committee Records of IAM Delegate Jackie Boschok, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 7/3)
        - WSLC (WA State Labor Council) Women's Committee Records of IAM Delegate Jackie Boschok, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 7/4-5)
        - WSLC (WA State Labor Council) Women's Committee Records of IAM Delegate Jackie Boschok, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 7/6)
        - WSLC (WA State Labor Council) Women's Committee Records of IAM Delegate Jackie Boschok, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 7/7-8/1)
      - Part 5: Snohomish County Labor Council (SCLC)
        - Snohomish County Labor Council (SCLC) Documents, 1992-2011 (Box-folder 8/7-8/8)
        - SCLC Community Services Committee (CSC)
          - SCLC Community Services Banquet programs, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 8/6)
          - Snohomish County Labor Council (SCLC) Community Services Committee (CSC) Records, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8/2)
          - SCLC CSC Records Kept by Recording Secretary Jackie Boschok, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 8/3-5)
    - United Way Snohomish County (UWSC), Subseries B
      - United Way of Snohomish County (UWSC) Leaders in Giving Reports, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 13/5)
      - United Way of Snohomish County (UWSC) Campaign & Labor Partnership Documents, 1995-2009 (Box-folder 13/6-7)
    - Boeing Company Records, Subseries C
      - Boeing Company Reports, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Boeing Company Materials, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Boeing Company Materials, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Class Action Settlement and Fairness Hearing: Beck v. Boeing, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Boeing Company Materials, 2000-2009 (Box-folder 2/5-6)
      - Boeing Directory, 2001 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2003 (Box-folder 14/2)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2004 (Box-folder 14/3-4)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2005 (Box-folder 14/5)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2006 (Box-folder 14/6)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2007 (Box-folder 14/7)
        - Boeing Employee Community Fund (ECF) Everett Campaign Leadership Team Records Kept by Jackie Boschok, 2008 (Box-folder 14/8-9)
  - JACKIE BOSCHOK PERSONAL RECORDS, SERIES II
    Series II is divided into four subseries based on subject matter: Subseries A: Jackie Boschok’s Union Involvement, Subseries B: Jackie Boschok’s Work History, Subseries C: Jackie Boschok’s Political Involvement and Subseries D: Seattle Goodwill Games/Rotary District 503 Goodwill Exchange. Within each subseries, files are arranged chronologically.
    The series consists of correspondence, certificates, official appointments, employee records, coursework, and pamphlets related to Jackie Boschok’s personal employment, education, politics and union involvement.
    - Jackie Boschok's Union Involvement Documents, 1987-2009; Subseries A
      - Evergreen State College Summer School for Trade Union Women (1st & 2nd), 1987-1988 (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Personal Letters and Documents for Jackie Boschok Regarding IAM Membership/Leadership, 1987-2009 (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Misc Membership Cards for Jackie Boschok, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Jackie Boschok's Work History, Subseries B
      - Paperworkers Union at St. Regis Paper Company in Tacoma, WA, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 12/3)
      - Jackie Boschok's Boeing Shop Folder, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Jackie Boschok's Boeing Work History, 1980-2007 (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Jackie Boschok's WA State Pesticide License Information, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Boeing Personal Benefits Reports, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Jackie Boschok's Political Involvement, Subseries C
      - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) Pamphlets, 1980 (Box-folder 12/4)
      - Pro-Choice Washington, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 7/2)
      - WWU (Washington Women United), 1989-1995 (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Jackie Boschok's Political Documents, 1992-2008 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Seattle Goodwill Games/Rotary District 503 Goodwill Exchange, 1990-1991; Subseries D (Box-folder 12/10)
  - PUBLICATIONS, SERIES III
    Series III is divided into three subseries by creator: Subseries A: IAM Publications, Subseries B: CLUW Publications and Subseries C: Year by Year: 75 Years of Boeing History. Subseries A and B are further divided by name of publication, and files are arranged chronologically within these sub-divisions.
    The series is a collection of journals, newspapers and newsletters published by the International Association of Machinists (IAM), the Coalition of Local Union Women (CLUW) and Boeing. While some serial publications can be found scattered throughout the corresponding files in Subseries A: Jackie Boschok Professional Records, the bulk of these materials are located in Series III.
    - IAM Publications, Subseries A
      - Part 1: 751 Aero Mechanic Newspaper
        - Guide to Aero Mechanic Articles on Jackie Boschok/Women's Committee and Miscellaneous Articles, 1991; 2010 (Box-folder 1/1)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 1/2)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1/3)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1/4)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 1/5)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 1/6)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1/7)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 1/8)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1/9)
        - 751 Aero Mechanic Newspapers, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Part 2: The Machinist Newspaper
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 1988-1992 (Box-folder 1/11)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 1993-1994 (Box-folder 1/12)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 1/13)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 1997-1999 (Box-folder 1/14)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1/15)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 2002-2004 (Box-folder 1/16)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 2005-2007 (Box-folder 1/17)
        - The Machinist Newspapers (Published by IAM), 2008-2010 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Part 3: Action Bulletin Journal
        - Action Bulletin Journal, 1993 (Box-folder 5/10)
        - Action Bulletin Journal, 2007 (Box-folder 5/9)
        - Action Bulletin Journal, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - CLUW Publications, Subseries B
      - Part 1: CLUW News Newsletter, 1993-2011 (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Part 2: Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) - Puget Sound Chapter Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Year by Year: 75 Years of Boeing History, 1991; Subseries C (Box-folder 2/7)
  - EDUCATIONAL/TRAINING MATERIALS, SERIES IV
    Series IV is divided into five subseries based on the subject matter of the materials: Subseries A: Union Educational Materials, Subseries B: Legal Educational Materials, Subseries C: Workplace Training Materials, Subseries D: Technology Training Materials and Subseries E: Sexual Harassment/Domestic Violence/Workplace Violence Resources. Subseries A is further divided by creator. Files within each subseries are arranged chronologically.
    Series IV consists of handbooks, training manuals, pamphlets, presentation materials and reports relating to various types of education: union (negotiating/collective bargaining), legal, workplace, technology and sexual harassment/domestic violence/workplace violence.
    - Union Educational Materials, Subseries A
      - Part 1: IAM Educational Materials
        - Empowerment: A Handbook for Union Women, 1982 (Box-folder 10/20-21)
        - CLUW Leadership Training Series: Color Me Union!, 1983 (Box-folder 10/22-23)
        - IAM Training Manual: The Placid Harbor Glossary for the Unionist, circa 1990s (Box-folder 4/1)
        - IAM Placid Harbor Education Center Leadership I School Training Materials, 1993 (Box-folder 1/19-1/20)
        - IAM District 751 Strike Preparation: Community Services Training, 1995-2005 (Box-folder 13/3)
        - IAM Placid Harbor Education Center Leadership II School Training Materials, 1997 (Box-folder 1/21-1/22)
        - IAM Training Materials: The Blitz, 1997 (Box-folder 4/4)
        - IAM Training Manual: High Performance Work Organization Partnerships, circa 1997 (Box-folder 4/5)
        - IAM Training Manual: Collective Bargaining Clauses - Part I - Model Language, October 1999 (Box-folder 4/8)
        - IAM Training Materials: IAM Virtual Lodge (VLodge.net), 2001 (Box-folder 4/9)
        - IAM Training Materials: Collective Bargaining, 2004 (Box-folder 4/12)
        - IAM Training Materials: Service Contract Act, December 2004 (Box-folder 4/14)
        - IAM Training Materials: Communication, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 4/17-18)
        - IAM Training Manual: Bargaining to Organize, 2005 (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Part 2: Union Counselor Course (co-sponsored by the Snohomish County Labor Council & United Way of Snohomish County) Training Materials, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 13/4)
      - Part 3: California School Employees Association Training Materials: The Art of Negotiating, circa 1993 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Legal Educational Materials, Subseries B
      - Schwerin Campbell Bernard Training Manual: Arbitration Without Lawyers, 2003 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Schwerin Campbell Bernard Training Manual: How to Help Disabled Workers, circa 2003 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Schwerin Campbell Bernard & Iglitzin LLP Training Materials: Strategic Corporate Research (Organizing), 2007 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Workplace Training Materials, Subseries C
      - US Department of Labor - Women's Bureau Resources, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 6/11)
      - IAM Manual: Workplace Drug Testing, 1988 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Prime Time: A Preretirement Planning Workbook for Boeing Employees and Their Spouses, 1990 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Training Manual: Principles of Materials Management, 1995 (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Boeing Training Manual: The Women's Millennium - Changing the Way We Do Business, 1998 (Box-folder 4/7)